<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>History</title>
    <author email="michal.d08@gmail.com">Michał Dobaczewski</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="History">

		<p>
			Svarog is based on the now defunct "signalml" (uncapitalized, as opposed to
			SignalML) project, which was begun in 2007 under supervision of
			<a href="http://brain.fuw.edu.pl/">Zakład Fizyki Biomedycznej, IFD UW</a>. 
			The development of <i>signalml</i>
			was being funded with a Polish science grant. A software company,
			<a href="http://www.cc.com.pl/">CC Otwarte Systemy Komputerowe Sp. z o.o.</a>,
			was contracted to develop the initial version. The following people were
			significantly involved in development (or management) led by CC:
		</p>
		
		<ul>
			<li><a href="team-list.html">Michał Dobaczewski (2007-March 2008)</a></li>
			<li>Oskar Kapala</li>
			<li>Grzegorz Kaczor</li>
			<li>Grzegorz Blinowski</li>
		</ul>
		
		<p>
			(links to the current team list are provided for people who are still 
			involved in	the development of Svarog) 
		</p>
		
		<p>
			In February 2009 the Svarog project was started as an effort led by
			enthusiasts. The code of <i>signalml</i>, which had been released 
			on terms of the	GNU GPLv3 license, was chosen as a starting point. 
			The two projects are formally separate in order to disassociate Svarog
			from any remaining issues related to the contract between ZFB and CC.
			As far as we (the Svarog team) know, the <i>signalml</i> project is now
			effectively dead, unmaintained, unsupported and will not be
			continued (other than as Svarog).
		</p>
		
		<p>
			The old signalml repository (import from CVS) can be viewed 
			<a href="http://escher.fuw.edu.pl/git/signalml-cvs.git">here</a>, but
			using this code for any purpose is highly discouraged (use Svarog instead),
			and no commit priviledges will be granted to anyone other than the employees of
			CC.
		</p>
									
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
