<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <author email="michal.d08@gmail.com">Michał Dobaczewski</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <!-- The body of the document contains a number of sections -->
    <section name="Welcome to Svarog">

		<p>
			Thanks for visiting Svarog's site. We hope you will find the software
			usefull and the information provided sufficient. If you have any questions
			do not hesitate to ask someone from the team.
		</p>

		<subsection name="What is Svarog?">
		
			<p>
				Svarog is intended to be a signal viewer, annotator, analyzer and recorder.
				Support for recording is not yet implemented in any form, and exists only
				in plans for the future. Support for signal analysis methods is preliminary. 
			</p>
			
			<p>			
				Svarog stands for <b>S</b>ignal <b>V</b>iever, <b>A</b>nalyzer 
				and <b>R</b>ecorder <b>o</b>n <b>G</b>PL. It's a rather loose acronym. 
				Svarog is also the name of a god (or deity) of the Sun, fire (and 
				of the smiths) in the religion of the ancient Slavic peoples. 
				Svarog used to be a prominent deity in central and eastern Europe prior to 
				christianization in the Middle Ages. 				
			</p>
		
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="The signals">

			<p>
				Svarog is not intended to handle very simple signals (for example stereo
				sound files). It was designed with more complex signals in mind,
				epecially biosignals, such as EEG or MEG, where the signal has
				few dozens of channels and is often up to 10 hours in length.
			</p>

		</subsection>

		<subsection name="Relation to SignalML">
		
			<p>
				Svarog uses SignalML to load signal files. Currently only SignalML 1.0 is supported
				but including SignalML 2.0 support is on the roadmap.
			</p> 
		
		</subsection>
		
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
