<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>Overview</title>
    <author email="michal.d08@gmail.com">Michał Dobaczewski</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Welcome to Svarog">

		<div style="display: block; float: right; width: 260px; padding-left: 10px; margin-bottom: 10px; background-color: #FFFFFF;">
			<div style="border: 1px solid gray; padding: 5px; background-color: #FFFFFF;">
				<p>
					Svarog is <a href="http://www.fsf.org/">Free Software</a>!
				</p>
				<p>
					You can 
					<a href="downloads.html"><span style="white-space: nowrap;">download and use</span></a>
					the software for free as well as
					<a href="source-repository.html"><span style="white-space: nowrap;">modify it</span></a>
					according to the terms of the
					<a href="license.html"><span style="white-space: nowrap;">GNU General Public License, Version 3</span></a>. 
				</p>
				<p>
					The latest version available is
					<a href="downloads.html#0.5.0"><span style="white-space: nowrap; font-weight: bold;">Svarog 0.5.0</span></a>.
				</p>
			</div>
		</div>

		<p>
			Thanks for visiting Svarog's site. We hope you find the software
			usefull and the information provided sufficient. If you have any questions
			do not hesitate to ask someone from <a href="team-list.html">the team</a>.
		</p>

		<subsection name="What is Svarog?">
		
			<p>
				Svarog is intended to be a signal viewer, annotator, analyzer and recorder.
				Support for recording is not yet implemented in any form, and exists only
				in plans for the future. Support for signal analysis methods is preliminary. 
			</p>
			
			<p>
				Svarog is written in Java and requires a Java virtual machine to run.
				Only version 1.6.0 and later are supported.
				We recommend you use the virtual machine distributed by Sun Microsystems.
				It can be obtained from <a href="http://java.sun.com/">Sun's Java site</a>.
			</p>
			
			<p>
				While some parts of the code are relatively well tested, this software 
				as a whole <b>should be considered a beta</b>. This means that there are likely
				some less obvious bugs lurking in the code and that data loss is
				more likely than it is with stable software. 
			</p>
						
			<p>			
				Svarog stands for <b>S</b>ignal <b>V</b>iever, <b>A</b>nalyzer 
				and <b>R</b>ecorder <b>o</b>n <b>G</b>PL. It's a rather loose acronym. 
				Svarog is also the name of a god (or deity) of the Sun and fire (and 
				of the smiths) in the religion of the ancient Slavic peoples. 
				Svarog used to be a prominent deity in central and eastern Europe prior to 
				christianization in the Middle Ages. 				
			</p>
		
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="The signals">

			<p>
				Svarog is not intended to handle very simple signals (for example stereo
				sound files). It was designed with more complex signals in mind,
				epecially biosignals, such as 
				<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Electroencephalography">EEG</a>
				or <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Magnetoencephalography">MEG</a>, 
				where the signal has
				a few dozens of channels and is often up to 10 hours in length.
			</p>

		</subsection>

		<subsection name="Relation to SignalML">
		
			<p>
				Svarog uses SignalML to load signal files. Currently only SignalML 1.0 is supported
				but including SignalML 2.0 support is on the roadmap.
			</p> 
		
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="Project goals">
		
			<p>
				The long term goals of Svarog are (in no particular order):
			</p>
			
			<p>
				<b>To bridge the gap between the lab</b> 
				(software accompanying scientific publications) 
				<b>and the clinic</b> (software used as aids in solving real-life
				problems) by providing software which is easy enough to use for people
				with little technical experience, and at the same time, flexible enough
				for people who experiment to develop and improve clinically applicable
				signal analysis methods. While such perfect marriage might be difficult
				to achieve completely, we believe that there is room for improvement over
				the current situation, in which — from our experience — these two worlds
				are largely separate.
			</p>
			
			<p>
				<b>To provide a platform for easy exchange of data and of signal
				analysis methods</b> in order to enable closer cooperation between various
				scientists and institutions working in the field of neuroscience. As stated
				in the introduction, the current situation is that it is difficult for one lab
				to verify the results obtained at another lab, mainly due to incompatibilities
				in data formats and software, and often also due to licensing problems
				associated with software. Creators of commercial systems have little interest
				in addressing such problems, especially when they bundle the software
				with their own hardware, and promote the whole suite. We believe that
				this situation hampers thorough peer review of results and clinical testing
				of promissing signal analysis methods.
			</p>
			
			<p>
				<b>To provide a free platform for signal recording</b>. Recording biosignals
				such as EEG usually requires more sophisticated equipment than,
				for example, recording the latest demo tape of your garage band. There
				is little that could be done about the cost of required hardware. There
				is no reason however, why a free software for registration of such signals
				could not exist. Considering that equipment vendors often add a significant
				price premium just for slapping their proprietary software on top of
				third party hardware (amplifier, ADC, etc.), the existence of such a free
				software could reduce the overall cost of installing any diagnostic (or scientific)
				signal recording equipment. For some less than rich countries or
				institutions it might make the difference between having and not having
				such equipment at all. While the 
				<a href="http://bci.fuw.edu.pl/">Open BCI project</a> seeks to provide a
				low level interface for working with hardware, Svarog could become the
				high level interface in which the signal captured is viewed, preprocessed
				and saved to disk.			
			</p>
			
			<h4>Short term goals</h4>
			
			<p>
				The short term goals of the project amount to a major spring cleaning effort, and are (in order):
			</p>
			
			<ul>
				<li>
					to complete the switch to using maven and clear remaining issues
					with using it;
				</li>
				<li>
					to build and configure all the required infrastructure
					(repositories, bug tracker, etc.);
				</li>
				<li>
					to review the code inherited from <a href="history.html">signalml</a>,
					fix outstanding bugs and complete features which aren't fully
					complete or operational;
				</li>
				<li>
					to review the situation with Matlab Builder JA and decide if it can
					be used at all;
				</li>
				<li>
					to work towards changing Svarog from a monolithic application it is
					now to a more modular application. As a result of this a lot of
					code is going to be moved out of Svarog into modules;
				</li>
				<li>
					to sanitize and document the code to make it easier for other people 
					to start participating in the project;
				</li>
				<li>
					to improve testability and increase the number of tests, which at this point
					are very few;
				</li>
			</ul>

			<p>
				After the above is achieved, we can work on extending the functionality of Svarog
				to achieve the long term goals.			
			</p>
			
		</subsection>

		<subsection name="How can I get involved?">
		
			<p>
				Svarog's team is very small given the needs, and there is a lot that you could do.
				<a href="faq.html#contribute-programmer-java">The FAQ</a> has a section on ways in which people can get involved. 			
			</p>
			
			<p>
				As a person involved in Svarog you cannot expect that your software will be used
				by great many people. This is a professional software targeted for a relatively
				narrow group of specialists: clinicists, physicians and scientists. On the other
				hand Svarog addresses concerns which directly relate to people's health and
				wellbeing. It has potential to improve the life of some people, somewhere, and
				as such is an important project. 
			</p>
					
		</subsection>
		
    </section>

  </body>

</document>
