<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
	  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

  <properties>
    <title>History</title>
    <author email="michal.d08@gmail.com">Michał Dobaczewski</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="History">

      <p>
	Svarog is based on the now defunct "signalml" project (uncapitalized,
	as opposed to SignalML - the description format), which began in 2007 under the supervision of
	the <a href="http://brain.fuw.edu.pl/">Department of Biomedical Physics</a> of
	the Institute of Experimental Physics, Warsaw University.
	The development of <i>signalml</i> was being funded with a scientific grant.
	A software company, <a href="http://www.cc.com.pl/">CC Otwarte Systemy Komputerowe Sp. z o.o.</a>,
	(CC) was contracted to develop the initial version. The following people were
	significantly involved in development (or management) led by CC:
      </p>

      <ul>
	<li><a href="team-list.html">Michał Dobaczewski</a> (2007-March 2008)</li>
	<li>Oskar Kapala</li>
	<li>Grzegorz Kaczor</li>
	<li>Grzegorz Blinowski</li>
      </ul>

      <p>
	<small>(links to the current team list are provided for people who are still
	involved in	the development of Svarog)</small>
      </p>

      <p>
	In February 2009 the Svarog project was started as an effort led by
	a team of enthusiasts. The code of <i>signalml</i>, which had been released
	by the Department of Biomedical Physics on terms of the GNU GPLv3 license,
	was adopted as a starting point. The two projects are separate in order to
	disassociate Svarog	from any issues related to the contract under which
	<i>signalml</i> had been developed, as well as to change the name to one that
	would not be easily confused with SignalML.
      </p>

      <p>
	As far as we (the Svarog team) know, the <i>signalml</i> project is now
	effectively dead, unmaintained, unsupported and will not be
	continued, other than as Svarog.
      </p>

      <p>
	The old signalml repository (imported from CVS) can be viewed
	<a href="http://escher.fuw.edu.pl/git/signalml-cvs.git">here</a>, but
	using this code for any purpose is highly discouraged (use Svarog instead).
	No commit priviledges for the old repository will be granted to anyone
	except CC employees.
      </p>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>
